Reading book covers, part two.
In the last session we just looked at the colors and we called these little packages of goodies books.
The child now knows the word book and this is a book cover that gives you an idea of what the book might be like.
So the next step is to maybe choose two books and say hmmm, which one would you like me to read?
The child is going to base their decision simply on the colors and you may say why would you like me to read this book?
Oh, because there's a little girl in the picture.
Why would you like me to read this book?
Because there's a character.
The main thing you're showing at this point is you're giving the child a choice and you're allowing them to compare pictures and they're learning to compare genre.
In the next step, you have a book for example, The Three Little Pigs and you have America the Beautiful.
Most children will choose The Three Little Pigs, why?
Because it's cute and it's colorful.
You're showing them that oh this book here has a lot of pretty photos.
You're explaining what's on the cover in picture terms.
And this book, look how beautiful that is, it looks like it's outdoors with three little animals that might be piggies.
Which one would you like me to read?
You are showing the child how to make choices and decisions and how later in life, how to develop judgment.
That simple.
Where first you've shown books, the second step, you're asking them a choice by comparing two different genres.
That's book covers, part two.